Łukasz Cieśluk

Personal details

Residence: Dublin, Ireland

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/lukaszciesluk

Summary

Professional Java Developer with over five years extensive experience within financial, telco, advertising and commerce industries. Highly self-motivated focused on clean code approach combined with functional programming. Advocate of automation in projects and addicted to open source.

Experience

XII.2017 - current

Senior Software Developer, Bloomberg PolarLake Dublin, Ireland

I. Stock Market Index Data

Stack: Java 8, Spring Boot, Maven, Guava, JUnit, AssertJ

IV.2017 - XI.2017

Senior Software Developer, Datalex Limited Dublin, Ireland

- I. Develop application for storing / managing flights and other additional services
- 2. Bring code style within clean code approach and new practices in terms of development and testing $\,$
- 3. Compose performance scripts in JMeter
- 4. Perform code reviews along with mentoring other developers

Stack: Java 8, Gradle, RESTEasy, MongoDB, Morphia, JUnit, Mockito, Hamcrest, JMeter

VIII.2015 - III.2017

Software Developer, Brandtone Limited Dublin, Ireland

- I. Develop primary campaign management system that engages consumers through different channels like IVR, SMS and USSD. First developer of Konnect online engagement platform which empowers marketers to maximize ROI and build deep relationships with consumers. Developer of Trader solution which helps traders improve selling their products
- 2. Cooperation with QA's, DevOps, DBA's, Architects and other Developers to build software which meets business requirements and KPIs
- 3. Participate in Agile Sprint planning, backlog refinement and retrospectives
- 4. Experience of working in environment which requires excellent troubleshooting, analytical skills, ability to be self-organised, strong interpersonal, communication skills and experience with a number of stack components and tools
- 5. Perform code reviews
- 6. Documentation enhancement

Stack: Java, Spring (MVC, Data, Batch, Integration), Maven, Oracle, Guava, Git, Grunt, Bower, Flyway, Docker, ActiveMQ, AWS*, Angular*, React*, Redux*, Webpack* (* - beginner)

VIII.2014 - VI.2015

Senior Java Developer, Digital Virgo S.A. Department of Development and Services

Warsaw, Poland

- I. Constantly cooperation with business analyst to fulfill client requirements and estimate particular modules of system
- 2. Collaboration with developers responsible for frontend
- 3. Bug fixing ad hoc appearing
- 4. Preparation of technical documentation
- 5. Develop mobile Value Added Services e.g. massive SMS sending service. Design dedicated standalone client for lottery system. Support actions of developers involved in mobiParking project
- 6. Implement SMS Payment Gateways responsible for charging clients for paid content and services

Stack: Java, Spring, Maven, Oracle, Git, Swing, Python

XI.2013 - VII.2014

Software Developer, AgreeYa Mobility Poland Sp. z o.o. Warsaw, Poland

- Develop supply system in accordance with customer requirements dedicated for medical industry
- 2. Direct cooperation with client in order to selection of technologies and solutions applied in application
- 3. Composition of technical documentation of produced software

Stack: Java, Python, Django, jQuery

VII.2012 - X.2013

Software Developer, Bank Gospodarstwa Krajowego Architecture and Monitoring Division

Warsaw, Poland

- I. Main role in develop new extensions of system responsible for monitoring bank infrastructure e.g. execution of money transfers, network stability, availability of databases and other banking systems
- Support supervisor during creation of new data models and graphs commissioned by Bank management and other departments
- 3. Overall system administration and maintenance

Stack: Perl, MySQL, Nagios

The intern was founded in the XVII edition of competition "Grasz o Staż" organized by PwC

VII.20II - IX.20II

Software Developer (intern), Telekomunikacja Polska S.A. Networks and Service Platform Division,

Department of Management Platforms Service, Warsaw, Poland

Develop tool improving the efficiency of administrator work around collecting and analysing Call Detail Records (CDR) used for billing customers for paid services

Stack: Java, Perl, Postgre SQL.

The intern was founded in the XVI edition of competition "Grasz o Staż" organized by PwC

VII.2010 - IX.2010

Software Developer (intern), Orange Poland S.A. Networks and Service Platforms Division, Department of ICT Systems Warsaw, Poland

Support administrators in the current surveillance and response to failure of IT systems responsible for the proper operation of the GSM/UMTS mobile networks. Develop tools to improve and enhance operational efficiency

Stack: Perl, Bash

The intern was founded in the XV edition of competition "Grasz o Staż" organized by PwC

Education

II.20II - X.20I2

Politechnika Białostocka (Białystok, Poland)

Faculty of Computer Studies

Degree: MSc

Specialization: Smart Internet Technologies

Thesis title: Analysis tools used to implement the concept of Telco 2.0

The master thesis was carried out in collaboration with <u>Orange Poland S.A.</u> under initiative Orange Labs Telco 2.0 University www.openmiddleware.pl

As the part of the thesis was developed application called Eventoo which aims to monitor the correlation between the area defined by event organizer for instance as a festival and the location of participants based on the operator localization interface to provide statistics and tools to collaborate with them

Framework - Spring Database - MongoDB UI - JSP, jQuery

Interfaces - Orange Location and SMS API, Facebook API

X.2011 - II.2012

Politechnika Łódzka (Łódź, Poland)

Faculty of Technical Physics, Computer Science and Applied Mathematics

Degree: MSc

Specialization: Systems in management and electronic commerce

Semester has been completed as part of a student exchange program called MOSTECH intended for students of technical universities

X.2007 - II.20II

Politechnika Białostocka (Białystok, Poland)

Faculty of Computer Studies

Degree: BSc

Specialization: Designing Application Systems

Thesis title - Secure communication using SMS

Platform - Java ME

Cryptographic algorithms - DES, AES

Scholarships

III.2010 - II.2011 Scholarship at Politechnika Białostocka

X.20II - II.20I2 University President Scholarship at Politechnika Białostocka

Certifications

XI.2015 Java SE 7 Programmer I (IZ0-803)

V.2016 ScrumMaster by Scrum Alliance (License no. 000527091)

Languages

Polish: native

English: upper-intermediate

Additional

Winner of XV, XVI and XVII edition of competition "Grasz o Staż" https://www.facebook.com/graszostaz Driving license category B

Languages | Java 7/8

Frameworks | Spring (MVC, Boot, Batch, Integration)

Databases Oracle, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis

Web Servlets, JSP, JSON, HTML, REST XML XPath, XQuery, XSLT, JAXB

Application server | Apache Tomcat

JPA | Hibernate

Message Broker | ActiveMQ

Testing | JUnit, Mockito, Hamcrest, DbUnit, WireMock, AssertJ

Version Control | Git, Subversion

Libraries | Guava, Apache Commons, JodaTime, Lombok

IDE Intellij, NetBeans, Eclipse

Operating Systems | Linux (Ubuntu), Windows Build automation | Maven, Bower, Gulp

Database Migration | Flyway

Cloud AWS (beginner)
Big Data Apache Kafka*
Virtualisation Docker

SDLC | Scrum (Agile)

Attlasian | JIRA, BitBucket, Confluence Continuous Integration | Jenkins, Nexus, SonarQube

Others | Postman, JMeter

Portfolio

Home - http://garciapl.github.io

Android Google Play Apps - http://play.google.com/store/apps/developer?id=GarciaPL

GitHub - http://github.com/GarciaPL
Tech Blog - http://garciapl.blogspot.com

^{* -} in progress